Patrick A. Levell

email patrick.a.levell@gmx.com - web palevell.github.io

Profile:

Results-driven Systems Analyst / Developer, Business Analyst, and Bitcoin enthusiast with broad-based experience in enhancing system functionality and end-user productivity. Accomplished professional who has earned a reputation for consistently meeting and exceeding aggressive objectives. Effective communicator possessing excellent interpersonal and relationship-building skills.

Computer Skills:

System Software	Applications	Development Tools	
Ubuntu Linux	Twitter API / Tweepy	PyCharm	
Oracle EnterpriseOne / JD Edwards OneWorld Xe	Libre Office, Open Office	PostgreSQL, MySQL, SQLite	
MS IIS/SharePoint	MS Office	SQL Server 2005/2008 (SSAS, SSIS, SSRS)	
macOS & iOS	WordPress	Rational Rose UML	
Windows XP/2008	MS Publisher	Visual Studio / Visual Basic	

Professional Experience

Programmer / Analyst:

- Working closely with executives, consultants, customers, suppliers, and end-users to define and refine requirements for Raymond's IT infrastructure
- Developing, designing, implementing, testing and maintaining the iWarehouseTM Fleet Optimization System, Raymond's first commercial software offering
- Supervising consultants and junior programmers working on a variety of projects
- Monitoring and troubleshoot issues in JDEdwards, data warehouse, and iWarehouse
- Developing strategy for streamlining operations by integrating business processes
- Using JDEdwards EnterpriseOne ERP forms and reports in combination with VB.Net and SQL Reporting Services in delivering optimized business solutions for National Accounts, Sales & Marketing, Warranty Services, and the Raymond dealer network

Computer Systems Analyst / Developer:

- Designing, developing, implementing, testing, and maintaining custom applications and reports in JDEdwards OneWorld ERP/MRP for Engineering, EMS/QMS, and other business systems
- Developing specialized reports & applications with JDEdwards, SQL queries, Excel, Access and VB/VB.Net/SQL Server
- Working closely with end users in defining and "fine tuning" requirements & creating documentation
- Training and supporting JD Edwards users in Finance, MRP, Sales, Purchasing, and Inventory modules

Freelance Programmer / Webmaster / Database Administrator:

- Mentoring bloggers, entrepreneurs, and Bitcoin startups in building and maintaining their online presence
- Performing as technical liason for clients with advertisers
- Administering customer databases
- Migrating web-sites to new servers

Related Volunteer Work

Community Manager:

People's Party of Canada Gatineau, Quebec (2019)

- Builiding a community for PPC candidates, volunteers, supporters, and critics
- Designing, developing, implementing, testing, and maintaining custom Twitter client
- Developing specialized reports for Twitter users
- Co-ordinating Twitter support teams for PPC candidates
- Participating in "hashtag campaigns" with the following objectives:
 - to assist Maxime Bernier being invited to the national Leaders' Debates
 - to draw attention to the PPC platform

Director of Communications:

Electoral District Association

People's Party of Canada London, Ontario (2019)

- Building and managing social media presence on Facebook for local candidates
- Promoting events for local EDAs and Maxime Bernier
- Promoting fund-raising and merchandise pages

Employers

Sole Proprietorship	London, Ontario	2012 to Present
The Raymond Corporation	Greene, New York	2007 to 2012
NUCOR Vulcraft – Florence	Florence, South Carolina	1997 to 2007

Education

Bachelor of Science, Computer Information Systems DeVry University, Chicago, Illinois Cumulative GPA 3.62 (Honours)